{
    "id": "f1bf113a1f8e44269735b36ac198160c",
    "title": "Tenses Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I will phone you when I ……………………",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, we use the simple present in the subordinate clause.",
            "answers": [
                "arrive",
                "will arrive",
                "would arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "He told me that he ……………………….. me.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "will help",
                "would help",
                "helps"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "People disliked her because she ………………………. arrogant.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, we use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "has been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We brought the food and they …………………………. the tickets.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "were buying",
                "had bought",
                "bought"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She was rich and famous but few people ………………………… her.",
            "description": "Like is not normally used in the continuous form. ",
            "answers": [
                "liked",
                "were liking",
                "are liking"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I waited for hours so that I ……………………………… her.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "can",
                "could",
                "would"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I went to bed early because I ………………………. not feeling well.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "am",
                "was",
                "had"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "If you need help, just ………………………….. me a call.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "give",
                "gave",
                "giving"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "While I ………………………….. a shower, I slipped on the floor.",
            "description": "We use the past continuous for a longer background action that was going on while another action interrupted it.",
            "answers": [
                "had",
                "am having",
                "was having"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "He talks as if he ………………………….. rich but he isn’t.",
            "description": "We use a past tense with a present meaning after as if and as though to show that a comparison is unreal.",
            "answers": [
                "is",
                "was",
                "had been"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "As well as …………………………. his knee, he broke his arm.",
            "description": "When we put a verb after as well as, we most often use the ing form.",
            "answers": [
                "injuring",
                "injured"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "While you ……………………………. TV, I was working.",
            "description": "Progressive forms are used in both clauses to talk about two actions that go on at the same time. ",
            "answers": [
                "watched",
                "are watching",
                "were watching"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}